（烈子(れつこ)）空前の盛り上がりを見せた
経理部の飲み会から 一夜 明け―
The drinking party for Accounting
last night saw sparks fly.
今日も また
会社での一日が始まります
Now, another day begins at the office.
（フェネ子(こ)）うえ～
完全に 二日酔いだよ
I am completely hungover.
飲み会の最後らへん
全然 覚えてなくってさ
I don't even remember
how the party ended.
はっ
（フェネ子）確か 烈子が…
Wait... Didn't Retsuko...
（延髄をたたく音）
（ハイ田(だ)）確か 烈子は
カラオケで何か歌…
I'm pretty sure Retsuko
sang some sort of...
（たたく音）
（烈子）幸運なことに
泥酔していた同僚たちは―
Luckily, my inebriated co-workers
don't seem to clearly remember last night.
その日の記憶が 全く ないようです
残る問題は…
The only problem left...
（足音）
（烈子）うっ
（トンのうなり声）
お… おはようございます
Good morning.
（トンのうなり声）
I'm terribly sorry about last night!
あ… あの… き… 昨日は
いろいろと すみませんでした！
酒の席とはいえ 数々のご無礼―
Drunkenness is not an excuse
for being as rude as I was!
申し開きのしようも
ございません
（トン）覚えてねえ
I don't remember...
（烈子）えっ？
昨日は飲み過ぎちまってな
I drank way too much last night.
あっ
♪～
RAGE
～♪
KARAOKE
（鷲美(わしみ)）じゃあ 烈子の―
So you managed to retain your reputation
as a responsible good girl?
真面目な いい子のイメージは
保たれたままってこと？
（烈子）そうみたいですね
（鷲美）何だ つまんない
-It seems so.
-Well, that's boring.
もう ひと事だと思って
Oh, please! I much prefer it this way.
あの ところで―
By the way,
さっきから ゴリ部長が 隣で
石になって固まってるんですけど
why is Director Gori frozen like that?
（鷲美）
ああ いいのよ 気にしないで
She's fine, don't worry.
でも…
But...
（鷲美）めんどくさいことに
なるから ほっときなさい
Let's not open that can of worms!
でも 石になるなんて
よっぽどですよ
But she has turned into a statue!
何か あったんですか？
Did something happen?
（鷲美）失恋したのよ
Heartbreak.
（ゴリ）でも まだ好きなの～！
But I still love him!
確かに私も 仕事を言い訳に
しすぎちゃったとこは あるわよ
I know I was always
using my job as an excuse!
でも 私だって
いろいろ我慢してたし―
I also put up with a lot from him,
but I was so forgiving!
いろいろ
許してあげてきたじゃない
それが いけなかったのかな？
Maybe that is where I went wrong?
何しても許されると
思わせちゃったのかな？
Did I make him think
I would forgive anything?
お互い 分かり合えるなんて
思っちゃうのが間違いなんだよね
I should have known that
we wouldn't understand each other.
We live in two different worlds,
after all!
だって ２人とも
違う世界を見てるんだもの
（ドライヤーの音）
（ゴリ）聞いてる？ 烈子
-Are you listening, Retsuko?
-Why did you follow me home?
だから 何で 家まで
ついてきちゃうんですか！
今夜は １人で
寝る気にならないのよ～！
I don't want to sleep on my own tonight.
いいかげん帰ってくださいよ
Just go back to your place already!
いいじゃない別に
烈子の部屋 一度見てみたかったし
You don't mind, do you? Besides,
I've always wanted to check out your room.
（ゴリ）あっ このＴシャツ借りるわね
（烈子）ちょっと～！
-I'm borrowing this T-shirt.
-No!
（ゴリ）ねえ ほんとに
好きな人いないの？
-Is there really nobody you like?
-No.
いません
-No nice suitors at work?
-Nobody!
（ゴリ）会社に いい人いないの？
（烈子）いません！
打っても響かない子ね
You don't want to spill the beans.
なら 想像くらい
してみてもいいんじゃない？
But it's nice to dream about it. Right?
この町の どこかに―
Your soulmate could be
somewhere in this city.
烈子にとって
運命の人がいるかもしれないって
（坪根(つぼね)）もう 何これ？
Oh, my...
れさすけ君 困るわよ
Resasuke, this is problematic.
“読めない領収書なんか
受け取れない”って いつも―
How many times have I told you
that we don't accept illegible receipts?
言ってるわよね？
（れさすけ）すいません
I'm sorry.
また ズボンのポッケに
入れっぱなしで 何日も―
Let me guess. You put it
in your back pocket and forgot about it?
ほったらかしにしてたんでしょう？
（れさすけ）はい
Yes.
（坪根）忘れて そのまま洗濯？
（れさすけ）はい
-And then you put it through the wash?
-Yes.
ハア… じゃあ 今回も自腹ね
That's another expense
you have to cover yourself.
（フェネ子）出た 自腹王子
The Out-of-Pocket Prince.
自腹王子？
-The Out-of-Pocket Prince?
-The spaced-out guy from Sales.
あの ぼーっとした営業の人
いつも あの調子で怒られてんの
-He always gets in trouble.
-I don't know him.
（烈子）あんな人 いたっけ？
（フェネ子）確かに
印象に残らないタイプだよね
Yes, he's not exactly memorable.
（ぶつかる音）
（角田(つのだ)）あっ 烈子先輩！
Ms. Retsuko!
あっ 角田さん
Hi, Tsunoda.
（角田）先日は ご飯
ごちそうになっちゃって―
Thank you for taking me out to dinner
the other night.
すみませんでした！ あっ
フェネ子先輩も こんにちは
Hello to you too, Ms. Fenneko.
（フェネ子）ヘヘ…
で いきなりなんですけど―
I know this is abrupt...
先輩 今
好きな人とか います？
-Is there someone you like?
-Huh?
は？
い… いないけど
No, there isn't...
じゃあ 合コン 参加しません？
Then would you join our singles mixer?
合コン！？
えー いいよ私はそういうの
A mixer?
No... I'm not into that kind of thing.
I know that you want a boyfriend.
でも 彼氏欲しいですよね？
行きましょうよ
出会いのチャンスですよ～
You should come.
This is your chance to meet some guys.
ねえ 先輩 出てくださいよ～
Come on, join us!
角田 烈子にその気がないんだから
やめたら？
Tsunoda, Retsuko isn't interested.
Cut it out.
何でですか？
-Why?
-Mixers are on the way out.
時代は
出会いなんて求めてないの
ある調査によれば 日本の
20代～30代の独身男性の75％―
A study in Japan has shown that 75% of men
独身女性の65％に―
and 65% of women
in their 20s and 30s have no partner.
交際相手がいない
という結果が出てる
つまり コスパの悪い恋愛に
見切りをつけて―
In other words, more and more people
are choosing the more economical option
of single life!
独り身を選ぶ人が増えてるの！
じゃあ フェネ子先輩も
参加します？
-With that in mind, do you want to join?
-What?
（フェネ子）はあ？
What do you mean, "With that in mind"?
Did you hear what I said?
何で“じゃあ”でつなげんの？
私の話聞いてた？
聞いてたけど
意味分かんないです～
I did, but I didn't understand.
ねえ フェネ子先輩も
“出る”って言ってるし―
Fenneko said that she's coming,
so you should come as well!
烈子先輩も来てくださいよ～
（フェネ子）出るって言ってないし
I never said that!
（鷲美･ゴリ）合コン！？
A mixer? Sounds good.
いいんじゃない？
でも 正直
そういうの苦手なんですよね
I'm not used to such activities...
烈子にとって
運命の人が来るかもしれないのよ
Your soulmate might be there!
運命の人って…
My soulmate?
私 そんな
ほれっぽいタイプじゃないですし
I don't fall in love that easily.
（鷲美）烈子
Retsuko, stop doubting yourself
and put yourself out there.
ごちゃごちゃ言ってないで
ステージに上がるのよ
（ゴリ）条件さえそろえば…
（鷲美）恋に落ちるときは…
In the right circumstances...
...anyone can fall in love...
...instantly!
（鷲美･ゴリ）一瞬よ！
ハア～
（ハイ田）なっんで お前まで
ぬるっと合コンに参加してんだよ！
Why did you give into
this mixer thing so easily?
（フェネ子）私が聞きたいよ
I don't know!
正直 見くびってた
I underestimated her.
角田があそこまで
相手を―
I didn't realize Tsunoda was so good
at dragging people into her schemes.
自分のペースに巻き込む
技にたけてるとは…
（２人）ハア…
でも安心して… 私 守るから
-But don't worry. I'll protect her.
-What?
あ？
血に飢えた
男どもの攻撃から―
I'll do my best to protect Retsuko
from those bloodthirsty guys.
烈子を全力で守るから
刺客として参戦するってことか
So you'll go as her bodyguard?
頼むわ フェネ子
Please, Fenneko!
You are my only hope.
お前しか頼りになるやつ
いねえからさ
任しといて
Leave it to me.
（烈子のうめき声）
（烈子）あっ
The Out-of-Pocket Prince!
自腹王子
同じ電車 使ってたんだ
He travels on the same train.
今まで全然 気付かなかった
I didn't have a clue.
一応 降りたときに
軽く挨拶くらい―
Maybe I should say hi
when we get off the train.
しといたほうがいいのかな？
いやいや
Wait, how would that
amount to anything?
下手に挨拶して
その後 どうするの？
話題もないし
微妙な距離感で―
We'd end up quietly walking to work,
but not quite together.
会社まで
行くことになんない？
っていうか そもそも―
Anyway, he doesn't even know me.
向こうは こっちのこと
知らないかもだし
あ～ 超めんどくさい
What a pain.
I wish I hadn't noticed him.
気付かなきゃ よかった
えっ？
（烈子）えっ えっ 会社…
Wait… The office...
What a weirdo.
超 変な人
（フェネ子）脱出経路は２つ
There are two escape routes:
the main entrance and the emergency exit.
正面入り口と 裏の非常口
何かあったら
はす向かいの交番に―
If you get in trouble,
the police station is opposite.
駆け込むこと
（フェネ子）分かった？
（烈子）う… うん
-Got it?
-Yeah.
フェネ子先輩
もっと肩の力抜いてくださいよ～
Ms. Fenneko, please, just chill out.
私 今日遊びで来てないし！
I'm not here to relax, you know!
烈子 変な男が狙ってきたら
私が守るからね
Retsuko, I'll protect you
if some freak sets his sights on you.
変な人なんて
来るわけないじゃないですか
No freaks are coming tonight.
何で そう言い切れんのよ？
How can you be so sure?
だって 来るの
うちの営業の人たちですよ
Because all of them
are from the Sales department.
（フェネ子）うちの営業？
（角田）そうですよ
-From the office?
-That's right.
社内合コンって
言ってませんでしたっけ？
Didn't I mention it was a company mixer?
（シャッター音）
（烈子）社内…
（フェネ子）合コン
-Company...
-Mixer?
（マヌ丸(まる)）どうも マヌ丸っす
-Hi, I'm Manumaru!
-Hello. I'm Rinta.
（りんた）
はじめまして りんたです
ほら 挨拶
Say hello!
（２人）自腹王子…
The Out-of-Pocket Prince.
（角田）えっ？
（フェネ子･烈子）何でもない
-What?
-Nothing.
ああ こいつは
れさすけっていいます
This guy here is Resasuke.
人数合わせで連れてきたやつなんで
飾りだと思ってください
He came to even out the numbers,
so don't mind him.
その言い方 ひどくないですか？
Don't you think
that's a mean thing to say?
（マヌ丸･りんた）アハハ…
け… 経理部の烈子と申します
I am Retsuko from Accounting.
よろしく！
烈子ちゃん かわいいっすねえ
-Nice to meet you. You're cute!
-What?
えー…
You remind me of someone...
誰かに似てんなあ
あっ
サンリオキャラに似てるって
言われない？
Has anyone ever said
you resemble a Sanrio character?
ああ わりと言われる…
On occasion...
（フェネ子のうなり声）
（マヌ丸）角田 この子 誰？
（角田）経理部のフェネ子先輩です
-Who is this, Tsunoda?
-Fenneko, from Accounting.
はじめまして！
フェネ子ちゃんも―
Nice to meet you. You're cute, too!
かわいいっすねえ
（エコー）
Mixers aren't that bad after all...
（フェネ子）合コン 悪くないかも
（マヌ丸たちの笑い声）
（マヌ丸）俺そういうの
全然余裕だから
-Oh, that's easy-peasy!
-Seriously?
（角田）それ
本気で言ってます？
（りんた）それって
言い方 変えるとさ…
-To put it another way...
-Where did you hear that?
（フェネ子）
それ どこ情報？
（４人の笑い声）
（マヌ丸）いや マジ マジ…
（フェネ子）だから…
（りんた）いや ほんとかよ～
I missed my chance
to join the conversation...
（烈子）すっかり
会話から あぶれてしまった
まあ いいんだけど
not that I really mind.
でも つまらなそうにしてるのも
あれだしな…
I don't want to look bored, though.
えーと 話題 話題
What can we talk about?
あの… 昨日
電車で お見かけしましたよ
Hi, I saw you on the train yesterday.
いつも 田園都市線
使ってるんですか？
Do you always use the Den-en-toshi line?
会社の駅で降りずに
行っちゃいましたよね？
You didn't get off at the station
closest to work.
あれから どうしたんですか？
What happened after that?
えっとですね…
Well...
お前
マジで ふざけんなよ
You must be joking, buddy.
お前
マジで ふざけんなよ
（角田たちの笑い声）
（りんた）アハハ…
（フェネ子）ヘヘヘ…
（りんた）いや お前
面白いじゃないか なかなか
You're a riot!
（烈子）えっ 今 何か言った？
Did he say something?
（フェネ子たちの笑い声）
（りんた）何が出るかな 何が…
（マヌ丸たちの笑い声）
（烈子）声 ちっさ…
He is so quiet.
え？ すみません
Sorry. It's a little noisy...
ちょっと うるさくて
（フェネ子たちの話し声）
えっ？
Huh?
（操作音）
ADD FRIEND
RESASUKE
ADD
（操作音）
CONCERNING THE TRAIN...
I ARRIVED LATE.
SEND
Concerning the train, I was daydreaming.
I missed my stop and arrived late.
アハッ
May I ask you something?
Of course.
Why are you drinking coffee in a can?
I'm not fond of alcohol.
（烈子）ウフフッ
だからって
普通 缶コーヒー 飲まないでしょ
I understand, but why coffee in a can?
（フェネ子）ハイ田 ねえ ハイ田！
-Haida! Hey, Haida!
-Don't shout. I can hear you.
（ハイ田）
うるせえな！ 聞こえてるって
何かねえ 合コン
思ってたより 超楽しい！
Mixers are a lot more fun than I thought.
（ハイ田）
んなこと どうでもいいんだよ
I don't give a damn about that!
烈子は どうなった？
-How is Retsuko?
-She's fine. No need to worry.
（フェネ子）全然心配ない！
やっぱ　あの子
こういうの向いてないね
She isn't cut out for this scene.
何か ずっと下向いて
携帯いじってるし
She spent the entire party
tapping away at her phone.
（ハイ田）そっか…
I see.
（フェネ子）っていうか ハイ田
情けねえんだよ お前
Anyway, Haida, you're a wimp.
Go and ask her out already, you idiot!
さっさと告っちまえ バーカ！
I'm not cut out for partying.
Neither am I.
（烈子）ウフッ
Somehow, I feel really relaxed.
何だか すごく落ち着いた気分
まるで 私たちの周りだけ
何も風が吹いてないみたい
There is a certain stillness
enveloping us.
COFFEE
あれ？
Huh?
私 酔ってんのかな？
I might be getting drunk...
先輩？
Hello?
烈子ちゃん？
Retsuko?
（倒れる音）
（フェネ子）烈子？
-Retsuko!
-Retsuko, are you OK?
（りんた）おい おいおい
えっ 大丈夫かよ
（角田）烈子先輩
大丈夫ですか？
ちょっと 烈子ちゃん？
（烈子）おかしいなあ
いつの間に こんな飲んだんだろう
Strange...
When did I manage to drink so much?
（烈子）うっ
RESTROOM
（デス烈子の吐く音）
（烈子）うう…
（水洗音）
（れさすけ）大丈夫？
Are you OK?
あ… ありがとう
Thank you.
（ゴリ）条件さえ そろえば…
In the right circumstances...
（鷲美）恋に落ちるときは…
...anyone can fall in love...
...instantly!
（鷲美･ゴリ）一瞬よ！
ああ～
♪～
～♪
Subtitle translation: John Haguewood